A Guide to the Papers of Charles J. Affleck, 1803-1874
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles J. Affleck 1803-1874
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7083
31 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was originally deposited by Charles J. Affleck on April 9, 1963. The Library then purchased selected items from the original deposit on July 8, 1963.
Scope and Content
The collection contains legal notes, 1803-1819, of James Marshall, Frederick County, Va., court order for court to be summoned to try a negro woman slave for burning a barn of John Kemp, 1806 April 24. Indenture, 1803 Nov. 30 between Robert Newman and Eben Taylor, witnessed by Marshall.
A letter, 1812, from John Randolph declines to discuss politics and a letter, 1817, from St. George Tucker, sends payment. There are also six receipts, 1812-1857, for hire and sale of slaves in Northumberland, Augusta, and Jefferson counties, Va., one specifying clothing.
Civil War items include a receipt, 1861, to John S. Lupton for corn commendeered by Fitzhugh Lee [1835-1905]. Note stating that Robert B. Craddock is messenger for the Pres. of the C.S.A. signed by Joseph R. Davis. Passes, 1864-1865, designating R. Keppel and L. P. Samanni as members of the Printers' Guard of Richmond.
Also an eulogy, 1864, in poetic form, for Leonidas Polk, composed by a North Carolina woman; orders, 1865, assigning James Pollard to medical treatment; newspaper clippings about the Printers' Guard and Leonidas Polk's death; obituaries of John A. Pizzini; and a carte-de-visite of Leonidas Polk. A letter, 1873, from A. W. Reilly, mayor of Richmond, Va., concerns war orphans; and two letters, 1874 from John G. Mosby to John Beatty discuss a bill before the General Assembly
Miscellaneous items include an invitation, 1858 July 1, for a Richmond College graduating class party; a banquet menu for the Association of Confederate Surgeons and the Medical Society of Virginia; an unissued stock certificate for the Richmond Shooting Club; and a receipt for a donation to the Robert E. Lee Monumental Association.
Slavery Documents, 1812-1856: receipts for the sale or rental of slaves. Persons concerned included: John Chamberlain, Jonas Chamberlain, Edmund Chandler, James J. Cullen, T[homas T?] Fauntleroy [1823-1906] John Magill, William Maslen, Mordica Percell, George Shreck-hire, John C. Straughan, Jeremiah Tripett.
Contents List
- Indenture between Robert Newman to Eben Taylor, witnessed by James Marshall 1803 Nov 30
- Autograph order signed by James Marshall instructing the sheriff to form a court in Frederick County to try a slave woman arrested for burning a barn and stable 1806 Apr 24
- Notes on Frederick County court case (Clauson versus Boyd) in the hand of James Marshall 1806 Aug 7
- John Randolph, Georgetown, to Mr. Oliver thanking him for a gift and stating that he will not discuss politics 1812 Jun 5, ALS
- Receipt: sale of a slave by John C. Straughan, Northumberland County, to Edmund Chandler 1812 Jun 21
- St. George Tucker to Mr. James Rawlings sending check for insurance 1817 Feb 20, ANS
- Legal opinion by [James] Marshall concerning payment of debt and office of constable 1819 Mar 1, AMS
- Receipt: sale of a slave by John W. Chamberlain to Jonas Chamberlain, Jefferson County, Va. 1835 Dec 19
- Receipt: Hire of slave by Jonas Chamberlain from T.T. Fauntleroy (signed by John Magill) 1840 Apr 30
- Receipt: sale of slave to George Shreckhire by Michael A. Coiner et. al., Augusta County 1842 Dec 12
- Receipt: hire of slave woman by [Mordica Percell] from William Maslin; details clothing to be given to slave under the contract 1856 Oct 24
- Bill of sale of slaves from Jeremiah Tripett to Jonas Chamberlain, Jefferson County [?], Va. 1857 Jan 5
- Invitation to Richmond College graduating class party 1858 Jul 1
- Certificate of payment to John S. Lupton for corn commandeered by Fitzhugh Lee, signed by Lee 1861 Jun 23
- Col. Joseph R. Davis, aide-de-camp, stating that Robert Craddock is messenger to the President [of the C.S.A.] 1862 Mar 14, ANS
- Two passes designating R. Keppel and L.P. Samanni as members of the Printers' Guard of Richmond; with a newspaper clipping, 1874 [?] concerning the Printer's Guard and three obituaries of John A. Pizzini 1864 Jan 12, 1865 Jan 25
- Viola [?] to Jefferson Davis with a poem, a eulogy for Leonidas Polk, with a carte de visite of Polk and two newspaper clippings on his death 1864 Jul 12, ALS
- Orders assigning Capt. James Pollard, co. H, 9th Va. Cavalry, to medical treatment, signed by Alexander Yelverton Peyton Garnett 1865 Mar 6
- Mayor of Richmond A.W. Reilly to "Col." about war orphans 1873 Jan 29, ALS
- John G. Mosby to John Beatty concerning a bill before the General Assembly which was dropped from the calendar 1874 Jan 20, Jan 24, 2 ALS
- Menu from Banquet for Association of Confederate Surgeons and Medical Society of Va. sponsored by the Richmond Medical Profession n.d.
- Stock Certificate, unissued, for the Richmond Shooting Club n.d.
- Receipt for dollar donated to the Robert E. Lee Monumental Association by John Beatty, signed by Jubal A. Early and Peyton Johnson, Sr. n.d.